We begin by showing how the tutorial captions will be uploaded to YouTube.
The text of the captions, title, and description, will all be translated preceding upload.
On the left I have a language name reference.
YouTube Studio is shown.
I will complete one example upload of a caption, title, and description.
Begin by adding a language to the list.
Next I will upload the caption file which has already been translated.
I then copy and paste the title and description.
You can see that I have many more to upload.
Let's look at what translation work is ongoing in the background.
We see that I am using 'GitBash' and 'LibreTranslate'.
'LibreTranslate' can be downloaded and installed without cost, directly from the prompt while using 'GitBash'.
This exact setup is available in the HTML Drafting repository at 'GitHub'.
To begin the translation we must use the script named 'srt.sh'.
We must have 'LibreTranslate' served locally for this script to function.
Another important component of this system, which is not shown here is called 'JQuery'. This must be installed first.
With all of the same software in place, it is possible that you might duplicate this exact setup.
Now I will show another little piece of software which makes it easy to perform a manual transcription of the video.
Google wrote this program but, I told it what to do...
The 'enter' key gives the next caption box, and 'shift + ,' or 'shift + .' change the ending time.
I can cycle back and forth from the video using 'alt + tab', pausing the video using the 'spacebar'.
This gives a very tight workflow for manual transcription work.
This little program is actually very important. It assembles a JSON file which is used for the translations.
So then we have the full package, ready to be handed over to our translation software.
Having captions for so many languages is a good thing for the purpose of discoverability.
Now I will show you where the JSON file must be placed before we will be able to use the special script.
The folder name is '1_caption_inputs'.
I will now show how easily it can be transferred. The file can be dragged into place.
With 'LibreTranslate' running on your local machine you must open another 'GitBash' and then run the exact command shown on the screen:  . ./srt.sh
You can see that I have many more uploads to do. This is a lot of work!
I wish you the best in attempting this same process yourself.
Well done! Tutorial Over...